A Guide to the Randolph-Meikleham Family Papers, 1792-1882
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- M[ary] J[efferson] R[andolph] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1833 November 24, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Boston, MA, November 25. (Box-folder 1:48)
  Concerning various family illnesses, and meeting with acquaintances, the Coolidges, and Lucia Swett, in Boston. She says that Lucia Swett reminds her of "Dolly Cutts, but yet she is by no means ugly." She also says, "I am attending a course of lectures on the subject of natural history by the by, the lecture is every Tuesday night and the price of a ticket of admission is $1, but I paid nothing for mine as I found on arriving, that Mr. Bulfinch had already made sister Ellen and myself a present of our tickets. That you might not be jealous however of my superior advantages I must tell you that I do not expect to acquire any [special]? degree of knowledge from them, the introductory lecture delivered by a young man of the name [Ralph Waldo] Emerson was a beautiful one but I fancy the succeeding lecturers, for there are several, are not very distinguished."
- [Lewis Randolph] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1833 December 14, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked City of Washington, December 15. (Box-folder 1:49)
  Regarding his staying at a boarding house in Washington, and that "'tis reported about the City, that [he is] addressing Sall," and that he does visit her family often and flirts with her. He relates that Delia is expected soon, but not expected to "lie in until the Spring," and that her "reputation is defunct," and that Old Middelton had traveled with her all summer. He also tells Septimia to tell Sister C[ornelia] that unless Dr. [James T.] Barclay has stolen the "Notes on [the State of] Virginia," Barclay does not have them.
- L[ewis] R[andolph] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1834 March 24, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked City of Washington, March 26. (Box-folder 1:50)
  Concerning the "troublesome" women he is acquainted with, and the "annoying" fact that they all fall in love with him after his harmless flirtation. He goes on to mention his future wife, "Betty Martin," and provides an anecdote about a "Congressman from Indiana" offering a sizable bribe to convince her to go to Indiana. He compares Betty Martin to Septimia, describes her physical features, and laments that she may have a low state of finances.
- Matilda [Palmer] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1834 March 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; with partial wax seal; postmarked City of Washington, April 2. (Box-folder 1:51)
  Concerning various illnesses at her home, and the slow recovery of Frank.
- M[ary] J[efferson] R[andolph] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1834 May 2, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Boston, MA, May 2. (Box-folder 1:52)
  Concerning her travels to Cambridge and Boston, and her interactions with Martha Stearns and some gentlemen.
- L[ewis] R[andolph] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1834 June 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked City of Washington, July 1. (Box-folder 1:53)
  Lightheartedly describing his future wife [Betty Martin], and the appointment of [John] Forsyth as Secretary of State, and others to various posts.
- Czarina [Macomb] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 18[3]4 August 25, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked New York, August 26. (Box-folder 1:54)
  Concerning her sister Matilda's illness, and events on Long Island during her stay there.
- [Cornelia Randolph] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1834 October 12, AL, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked City of Washington, October 14. (Box-folder 1:55)
  Concerning marriages in Washington, and asking Septimia to bring various things with her on her visit there including "a piece addressed to Sir Walter Scott by Miss Gould [belonging to] Miss Elliot."
- Archibald Cary to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1834 November 4, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked University of Virginia. (Box-folder 1:56)
  A highly rhetorical letter detailing his sadness and madness for "the absence of his beautiful cousin." Relates going to the "State Temperance Convention," and discusses William Randolph's visit.
- Ellen [Bankhead Carter] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 183[4] November 8, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Charlottesville, VA, November 9. (Box-folder 1:57)
  Relating Ann's nearly fatal illness, and her recovery. Relates that Sally [Carter] is to marry Uncle Ben[jamin Franklin Randolph] the following week, but that he deserves a better wife, and Sally's uneasy relation with the rest of the family.
- G[eorge] W[ythe] Randolph to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1834 November 13, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; with partial wax seal; postmarked Norfolk, VA, November 17. (Box-folder 1:58)
  Concerning Mr. Trist's journey to Havana, and his studies. In a post script, he mentions a "richly merited" beating of Captain Newel by "an officer whom [Newel] had dismissed from service."
- Archibald [Cary] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], [18]34 December 15, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked University of Virginia, December 11. (Box-folder 1:59)
  Congratulates her on her engagement, and desires more details of her wedding plans. He laments the desertion of ladies from the University of Virginia, and claims that "the Ladies of Charlottesville are tired of the students or the reverse. [He doesn't] know which." Also relates to Septimia, "Your acquaintance A[rchibald] F. E. Robertson (the young man you saw at Davis' & thought so handsome) was shot in the back by an old fellow, while endeavoring to take a dead negro for our anatomical dissections- He is recovering and the old [colt?] will be sent to the Penitentiary."
- [Jane Randolph] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1835 January 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 1:60)
  Concerning the recovery of their mother, Martha Randolph, and her visit to the University of Virginia. Relates her brother's involvement in "violent excitement" in Washington.
- M[ary] J[efferson] R[andolph] to Susan B. Coolidge, 1836 July 25, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 1:61)
  Concerning her return to Edgehill, her travels with Septimia, and their mother's [Martha Jefferson Randolph] health. Her encounter with a "handsome young man" who conversed with her mother to the "astonishment" of the young ladies in her party.
- E[llen Bankhead] Carter to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1837 March 2, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Charlottesville, VA, March 8. (Box-folder 1:62)
  Concerning her confirmation, communion and her desire that her children and all of her friends do likewise, and her consolation during their time of the loss of her grandmother and Septimia's mother [Martha Jefferson Randolph].
- L[ewis] R[andolph] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1837 March 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked Little Rock, AK, March 20. (Box-folder 1:63)
  Concerning his situation in Little Rock, Arkansas, and his child. His desire that Septimia not go to John Carter's, who he would "give an Arkansas salutation on sight" were it not for Ellen [Bankhead Carter], and concerning fighting over their mother [Martha Randolph]'s will.
- Alice Meikleham to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1838 March 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 1:64)
  Concerning her desire to meet her future sister-in-law.
- C[ornelia] J. R[andolph] to Septimia [Randolph] Meikleham, 1838 August 16, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 1:65)
  About her desire that Septimia break a long silence, and various items that she will send.
- Mary J[efferson] Randolph to Susan B. Coolidge, 1839 January 4, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; with wax seal; postmarked New York, January 26. (Box-folder 1:66)
  Concerning her travel on the ship Norma from New York to Havana, discovering Septimia"s illness once in Cuba, and Septimia and Dr. [David Scott] Meikleham's new home.
- L[ewis] Randolph to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 183[ ] May 18, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked University of Virginia, May 13. (Box-folder 1:67)
  Mentions his new job as an editor for a literary magazine, and his love of women. Provides an extended description of Miss Charlotte T[aylor] and Miss Pollard. He asks for submissions by Mr. [Nicholas P.] Trist to his paper "The Chamelion," which "discuss[es] freely all subjects with the single exception of religious & these [they] excluded not wishing to furnish any ground for the reports already afloat about the infidelity of the institution" [The University of Virginia].
- Dolley Payne Madison to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1840 August 31, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:68)
  Original in Dolley Madison papers.
- S[eptimia] A[nn] R[andolph] M[eikleham] to Patsy Trist, [1842] Sunday, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:69)
  Describing an incident of domestic violence.
- Edward Everett to Unidentified, 1843 October 2, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. (Box-folder 1:70)
  Concerning information on the Cary estate.
- Ellen Coolidge to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1844 May 18, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:71)
  Concerning her nervous illness, her desire to keep it secret, and the expected return of her husband from China in June.
- Dolley Madison to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1844 December 5, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:72)
- Ellen Cutts to [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], 1845 October 12, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:73)
  Concerning Septimia's illness, and Ellen's desire for Septimia to move to Washington. Mentioning the conditions of various friends including Mr. and Mrs. Trist, and Mrs. [Dolley] Madison's recovery from illness.
- E. A. Donelson to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1846 June 2, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:74)
  Concerning Lewis [Randolph's] desire that Septimia take their mother's silver.
- Ellen Coolidge to Septimia [Randolph] Meikleham, 1846 October 24, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked. (Box-folder 1:75)
  Congratulating Septimia on the birth of her daughter, and describes her travels through Europe.
- Emily Hollingsworth to Dr. Meikleham, 1849 July 18, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:76)
  Thanking [David Scott] Meikleham for his help in her illness.
- "Letters of Administration Granted to Septimia A[nn] C[ary Randolph] Meikleham," 1849, DS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:77)
  Granting Septimia the administration of David Scott Meikleham's estate.
- Edward May to Mrs. [Septimia Randolph] Meikleham, 1852 May 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; with wax seal; postmarked. (Box-folder 1:78)
  Mentions various friends, and life in Paris. Mentions meeting Mr. Napoleon [III of France], who is "determined to give the people amusement instead of the liberty of which he has denied them," and briefly describes the physical characteristics of this "snobby looking individual."
- J[ohn Bulkeley] to "mine ancient sister," [ca. 1857 February 19], ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope and enclosed drawing. (Box-folder 1:79)
  Envelope claims note sent "from John Bulkeley a short time before his death." Asking her to accept a drawing of her by him, with the drawing enclosed on the verso of a calling card.
- H. H. [Marshall]? to S[eptimia Randolph] Meikleham, 1860 April 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:80)
  Concerning the dispensation of John St. George Randolph's estate.
- G[eorge] W[ythe] Randolph to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], 1860 October 14, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:81)
  Concerning the election of Lincoln, and his anxiety "as to what will be done by the South." He expresses his belief that Virginia will not secede "for it must be borne in mind that the western half of the State which contains nearly two thirds of the white population and controls the State Government, have very few slaves and are by no means so sensitive to the attacks of the abolitionists." With obituary that was formerly clipped to the letter.
- G[eorge] W[ythe] Randolph to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], 1864 December 22, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:82)
  Concerning his illness, arrival in Europe, and lamenting that his health required him to leave at such an important time [in the Civil War].
- Unidentified to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], 1873 August 27, AL fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:83)
  Concerning her eye problems, and various diseases. Also bequeaths Septimia two dresses upon her death.
- Charles [Stewart] Parnell to Septimia Randolph Meikleham, 1878 January 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:84)
  Thanking her for her letter, and providing her with his mother [Delia T. Stewart Parnell]'s address.
- Alice Meikleham to "My dearest Alicia," [18]78 May 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope. (Box-folder 1:85)
  Concerning daily activities, and a list of family silver.
- Delia T. S[tewart] Parnell to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], 1881 August 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:86)
  Concerning the route of her travels for Land League business, and suggests that Septimia's daughters should join the Ladies [Irish National] Land League.
- Delia T. S[tewart] Parnell to Septimia Randolph Meikleham, 1882 April 7, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:87)
  Inquires about Septimia's health, mentions her involvement with the [Irish National] Land League, and asks for boarding recommendations in Washington.
- Delia T. S[tewart] Parnell to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], 1882 April 15, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:88)
  Concerning her daughter's illness, and her appearance among the delegates to the [Irish National] Land League Convention in Washington. Also mentions her desire to return to Washington to see Septimia and to participate in [Irish National] Land League activities upon her daughter's recovery.
- Unidentified to Unidentified, [18]89 April 21, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope; postmarked. (Box-folder 1:89)
  Letter in French; with note in another hand that the author is an artist.
- Eleanor M[onroe] Bankhead to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.y. February 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; with wax seal; postmarked Charlottesville, VA, February 8. (Box-folder 1:90)
  Concerning their schooling and studies.
- A. E. McK[ean] to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.y. April 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:91)
  Asking her to accept a gift of poems, and thanking her for her excellent pupilage.
- Lewis Randolph to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.y. May 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked Richmond, VA, May 3. (Box-folder 1:92)
  Inquiring about the recent arrival of Miss Stearns, and his hope that Septimia will meet with Miss Carr.
- L[ewis] Randolph to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.y. July 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Charlottesville, VA, July 30. (Box-folder 1:93)
  Concerning his poverty at school and inability to purchase law books, but refuses her and Cornelia's offered financial assistance.
- Dolly P. M. Cutts to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.y. October 29, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:94)
  Concerning her purchase of one of "the Generals Badges" for Septimia.
- L[ewis] Randolph to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.y. November 19, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked Richmond, VA, November 19. (Box-folder 1:95)
  Concerning his lack of knowledge about the conditions of their relations, his desire to see Washington, and his various interactions with family friends in Richmond.
- Eleanor M[onroe] Bankhead to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.y. December 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked Charlottesville, VA, December 10. (Box-folder 1:96)
  Concerning her studies, and the burning of her Aunt Cary's house "by the mischief or carelessness of a little negro girl of a visitor's."
- Julia Vail to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d. Tuesday Morning, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf. (Box-folder 1:97)
  Asking to borrow some waltz music.
- W. D. Meikleham to "Dear Mamma," n.d. Tuesday, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:98)
  Concerning his housework blunders in Mr. Cox's absence.
- [Miss] Anna [Maria Sanith]? to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d. Wednesday night, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:99)
  Concerning a death in the family, and her desire to travel.
- [Mrs. Talbot]? to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.y. Thursday 10, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 1:100)
  Thanking her for helping her sell some tickets.
- Anne C. Lynch to Mrs. [Septimia Randolph] Meikleham, n.d. Friday, ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope. (Box-folder 1:101)
  Declining an invitation.
- Eleanor Monroe Bankhead to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 1:102)
  Concerning her gardening and the collection of flower seeds.
- Eleanor M[onroe] Bankhead to [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:103)
  An enclosure from a letter that tells Septimia not to show the letter.
- J. M. R. Bankhead to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:104)
  A child's letter.
- Barbara [ ] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:105)
  Concerning Mrs. McKean and Miss Spooner's school, and offering to lend Septimia any books she desires.
- Mrs. C. B[rown] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. Brittle along folds and torn. (Box-folder 1:106)
  Making a gift of a pair of gloves, and her sorrow at their separation.
- [Ellen Bankhead Carter] to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., AL fragment, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:107)
  Concerning her sewing projects, and relating an anecdote about Uncle Ben[jamin Franklin Randolph] assisting a student, Henry Dixon, in eluding the sheriff.
- R. P. C. to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:108)
  Suggesting that she go to the Smith's if invited.
- Caroline to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; address on verso. (Box-folder 1:109)
  sking her to meet her in the afternoon.
- [Miss] Lucy [Ellery] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:110)
  Inquiring about her interests, her life at school and in Virginia.
- Fanny to S[eptimia] Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:111)
  oping to see her that evening.
- Elizabeth Higginbotham to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:112)
  Sending her a black necklace.
- John Macomb to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:113)
  Providing her with Czarina Macomb's address.
- Dolley Payne Madison to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:114)
- Matilda [Palmer] to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:115)
  Asking to buy one of Septimia's dresses, and inviting her to a party.
- Matilda [Palmer] to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:116)
  Informing her that the Masons will also attend a dinner.
- Delia [T. Steward Parnell] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf. (Box-folder 1:117)
  Declining to walk with her that evening.
- Delia [T. Steward Parnell] to "My dear Madam" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:118)
  Concerning the recovery of her son, [Charles Stewart Parnell].
- Delia T. Steward [Parnell] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:119)
  Asking Septimia to visit.
- Pat to S[eptimia] Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:120)
  Glad to hear her "Grandpapa" [Thomas Mann Randolph] has recovered.
- C[ornelia] J[efferson] R[andolph] to Susan B. Coolidge, n.d., ALS fragment, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:121)
  Thanking her for an item.
- M[ary] J[efferson] R[andolph] to Sep[timia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:122)
  sking for the return of her thimble, and describing her view of the river.
- Meg Randolph to "Dear Tim" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:123)
  Concerning her fall down the stairs, and the consequent pain in her nose.
- M[ary] P[age] R[andolph] to S[eptimia] Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:124)
  Concerning her chickens, and gardening.
- M[ary] P[age] Randolph to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:125)
  Desiring to hear Septimia play the harmonica.
- M[ary] P[age] R[andolph] to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:126)
  Concerning the alterations to a dress for her sister Lucy.
- M[ary] P[age] R[andolph] to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:127)
  Concerning sending her baby.
- M[ary] P[age] R[andolph] to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:128)
  Asking her not to forget to "send the baby."
- Sophie to [Sep]tim[ia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:129)
  Asking if she will go to her cousin's that evening.
- [Bennet Taylor] to "The Misses Randolph," n.d., AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:130)
  Desiring a description of a party they had attended.
- Caroline [Ware] to [Sep]tim[ia Randolph Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:131)
  Inviting her to visit.
- Mary Winn to Septimia Randolph [Meikleham], n.d., ANS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:132)
  Inviting her to a party.
- Unidentified fragment, n.d., 1 p. (Box-folder 1:133)
  Contains scribbling, the days of the week, and Septimia's name.
- "Everyday life at Monticello," n.d., Ms, 7 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:134)
  Describing the daily routines at Monticello with particular attention to dining protocol, and to the epitaph on Thomas Jefferson's grave.
- "A Glimpse of the West in 1804" by Miss Meikleham, [ca. 1871], MsS, 7 pp. on 7 l. (Box-folder 1:135)
  A historical overview of Western development from the vantage point of sixty seven years later, and extolling "how short a time is required by the energetic and persevering to transform a wild uncultivated country into one teeming with the products of commercial and agricultural industry." Primarily concerning Meriwether Lewis and William Clarke's expedition, with an extended discussion of the Osage tribe and its myth of origins.
- Septimia Randolph Meikleham "Quiet Home Life of Mr. and Mrs. Madison," n.d., Ms, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:136)
  Reminiscing about her visits to Montpelier, the home of James and Dolley Madison, the conversation, and daily routines there, and her last visit after the death of James Madison. She recalls that "[James Madison] was a small man, but one scarcely noticed it, his manners were so dignified, and Mrs. Madison's were the same, both were full of benevolence & most agreeable genial companions."
- Miscellaneous Items, n.d., 10 items. (Box-folder 1:137)